hello and welcome to the 28th tutorial
on how to program a g-script 2.
in the last tutorial i showed you a bit
about classes and how you can drop them
down as npcs from weapons or other npcs
and
in this tutorial i want to continue
teaching about classes and how to use
them
so let's open our level editor
and drop down a new npc
let's put
client side
and then function on created
set image
fire dot gif which is an image that
everyone has but it doesn't look very
good so i don't think you should use it
don't lock
and then on timeout
function on timeout
set timer 0.5
nope
0.05 we don't want to be that slow
okay
in this code let's make let's make this
a fire script and what the fire script
is going to do is when you get too close
to it it's going to hurt you
okay let's do some math temp dot a is
equal to this dot x minus player dot x
what this line of code is going to do
it's going to find the
distance
um on the
x coordinate
between you and the mpc
and then put temp dot
b is equal to this dot y minus player
dot y
and what that's going to do it's going
to find the distance between
u and the npc on the y axis
and then let's put one more line temp
dot c is equal to
parenthesis a times a plus b times b
then to the square root
of the power of 0.5
which is also the square root of 2.
or you just square it square root it
so this is going to find
the distance in tiles between you and
the mpc
it's called the
pythagorean theorem i think
and you learn it in geometry at least
that's what i did
so let's put if
uh
if c is less than three
actually let's put
this.chat is equal to c
just to um
see if it works
save it
and upload
so it's telling us the the amount of
distance between the embassy and us
in tiles
but we don't really want all these
numbers after the decimal point so let's
open the script and put
int parentheses c it's going to round it
down to the nearest whole number
so now it's going to say 9 7
however many tiles we are away from it
let's open the script again
and put if c is less than three
and
player dot h p is greater than zero
because we don't want it to hurt you if
you're already dead
then player h p is equal to player.hp
minus zero point oh nice point five so
your hearts are going to go down by a
half a heart
each
0.5 seconds you're in it
so let's add a sleep delay so when you
get hurt it takes .5 seconds
and 0.05 seconds to
make you get hurt again
also let's put set annie
hurt so it makes it look like you're
hurt
okay
let's close that and see if it works
so as you can see it does hurt you i
just had my health pretty low so that's
why i died instantly let's go into it my
health's going down until i get out
you can go into the script and take out
the chat part now we don't need that
now let's go to level editor and copy
and paste this script
i mean the mpc multiple times
save it and run it
well
as you can see they're everywhere now
let's open the level editor again
and let's say we want to change one of
the scripts
we want to change the
distance from when you get hurt let's
change it from three to two so you have
to be closer to get hurt
well now we have to go through all the
npcs and change three to two
to two
this is pretty annoying especially when
you have the npcs in different
levels
and you have to load levels and it's
more than just one number that you want
to change there's an easier way to do
this let's delete all the excess npcs
then open the
original npc
copy everything
then let's go to our rc in the in the
scripts
open the classes part folder and add a
new class that's called
hurt
fire
okay
then we're gonna paste this npc script
into here
click apply
okay
now in the level editor
we're gonna open the npc
delete all this
and put
function on created
then join
and then the name of the class which was
hurt fire
and that's it
all of the
commands and functions from this script
i mean this class
are now going to be in this level npc
the same can be done for weapons
and whatever
so we can copy this and put it
everywhere we want
then upload the level
as you can see we have four npcs here
and they all run the same class script
okay
let's open the script again
and let's change the i mean the class
script and let's change the image from
fire
to fire sl
and
apply fire sl is an image that i have
you may not have it so you should
probably use something else
and we are going to update the level
by saying update level
and now all the
npcs update and they have the new class
script on them
we don't even have to open level editor
and change the scripts we have a join
class here and we just have to enter the
class whenever we want to change it this
is really useful
now we don't have to just have join
class we can have some more scripts down
here
and other functions
in the actual npc
but if you want to just add the
functions from this class then that's
how you do it
keep in mind that when you're using join
it must be on server side
not client-side but in the actual class
script you may
have the script on the client side if
you want to anyway that concludes this
tutorial
and i hope you understand how to join
classes now into weapons
and npcs
adding him into weapons is the same way
as adding him into npcs
anyway i will see you next time